# **DENIS SOLDATOV**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

clhost.work@gmail.com Jul 1, 1997 linkedin.com/in/clhost

#### OBJECTIVE

I'm a software engineer with 5 years of professional experience in FinTech. I'm longing to design and develop highly available, highly loaded, fault tolerant and event driven systems.

I believe in that system should be implemented with proper DDD approach to make system understandable and scalable without pain, being in touch with domain restrictions and using ubiquitous language.

#### SKILLS

Kotlin / Java

Spring Boot

Microservices

Domain-Driven Design

SQL

Postgres

Redis

Gitlab CI/CD

RabbitMQ / Apache Kafka

Software Development / Architecture

# **⊕** LANGUAGES

English | Intermediate

Russian | Native

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Engineer**

Mobile Card LLC

Feb 2020 - Aug 2023

Worked on a payment system which processed a millions of payments per day.

I participated in developing a completely new event-driven microservices platform as a replacement of a legacy system in order to achieve high availability, scalability and fault tolerance, working with DDD approach with strategic and tactical patterns. I gained experience in designing, developing and refactoring of all parts of the system.

Analyzed and improved the conversion of payments in order to increase the profits of the company.

Developed new payment gates for 2 banks to operation with (refill, withdraw operations).

Invented an open-source process inside the company by writing a lot of libraries that cover all infrastructure of the microservices platform to reduce time-to-market and have a routineless development.

I worked in the Platform team to reduce time-to-market by creating a CI/CD workflow for microservices that covers all parts of interaction with infrastructure. Also, I gained experience with designing and creating templates and manifests for microservices and writing CLI tools that helps developers to work comfortable.

Arch: DDD, Event Sourcing, CQRS, multi-layered architecture, event driven architecture, microservices.

Technologies: Kotlin, Spring Boot, Ktor, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Redis, Postgres, k8s. Gitlab CI/CD.

# Software Developer

Aug 2018 — Feb 2020

YOTA

Redesigned and developed payment system: breaking monolith into microservices, modernizing legacy codebase, optimization of existing services.

Worked on reconciliation of payment registers.

Developed an integration with other external payment systems.

Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Netflix OSS, Consul, RabbitMQ, Oracle, Gitlab CI/CD, Docker.

## **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science**

Aug 2015 - Jul 2019

Peter the Great St. Petersburg Polytechnic University

Grade: 4.2 out of 5.0.

Topic of my diploma: designing of a system for reconciling fiscal checks.

#### **Completed course**

Sep 2016 - Jun 2018

Technopolis (2-years program)

Grade: 4 out of 5.

2-year program from a leading IT company about how to build, design and maintain high load systems.

At the end of the program, in a group of 3 people we developed and defended a system that helps you to get directions for a walk.